<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on it-ninja</title>
    <link>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on it-ninja</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:54:19 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Error Disable</title>
      <link>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/switching-err-disable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:54:19 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/switching-err-disable/</guid>
      <description>Recovery  All detectors are on by default. All recovery modes are disabled by default. Default recovery timer is 300 seconds.  Min is 30 seconds.  detect and recovery modes configured globally.  Configure Timer interval switch(config)# err-disable recovery interval &amp;lt;30-86400&amp;gt;  Detect ASW1(config)#errdisable detect cause ? all Enable error detection on all cases arp-inspection Enable error detection for arp inspection dhcp-rate-limit Enable error detection on dhcp-rate-limit dtp-flap Enable error detection on dtp-flapping gbic-invalid Enable error detection on gbic-invalid inline-power Enable error detection for inline-power l2ptguard Enable error detection on l2protocol-tunnel link-flap Enable error detection on linkstate-flapping loopback Enable error detection on loopback pagp-flap Enable error detection on pagp-flapping pppoe-ia-rate-limit Enable error detection on PPPoE IA rate-limit psp Enable error detection on PSP security-violation Enable error detection on 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Security</title>
      <link>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/switching-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:18:19 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/switching-port-security/</guid>
      <description>Port Security  Port level security feature. Exclusive use from 802.1x. You cannot use both features on the same port. Modes  Shutdown: Default state, the port is placed into err-disabled mode. The LED switches off. Protect: Frames from the offending host are dropped. Restrict: Like protect frames are droped from the offending host and logged.  sticky used to ensure learned MAC survives a reload. THe MAC is saved in the running and startup configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>