<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bgp on it-ninja</title>
    <link>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/tags/bgp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bgp on it-ninja</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 21:41:19 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/tags/bgp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP Summarisation</title>
      <link>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/rouing-bgp-summarisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 21:41:19 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/rouing-bgp-summarisation/</guid>
      <description>Summarisation  BGP supports summarisation.  Where and how  In the route process aggregate-address &amp;lt;address&amp;gt; &amp;lt;mask&amp;gt; In the route process aggregate-address &amp;lt;address&amp;gt; &amp;lt;mask&amp;gt; (&amp;lt;no-summary&amp;gt;|&amp;lt;uppress-map&amp;gt;) [supress-map-name]  What happens  Without summary-only or suppress-map knobs both the aggregate and more-specific routes are advertised. There must be a route with a longer prefix that lies within the summary-address prefix for the summary-address to be advertised.  Tips  Convert the addres binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP Attributes</title>
      <link>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/routing-bgp-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 20:26:19 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/routing-bgp-attributes/</guid>
      <description>Attribute Types  Well-known mandatory: Must appear in all BGP updates. BGP speakers must undertand these.  AS_PATH. origin. next-hop.  Well-known descrentionary: Must be recognised by all BGP speakers but does not have to be included in every BGP udpdate.  LOCAL_PREF. atomic aggregate.  Optional Transitive:  aggregator. community.  Optional non-transitive:.  MED (multi-exit discriminator). Cluster List   Optional attributes Optional attributes that are those that not every BGP speaker will understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP</title>
      <link>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/routing-bgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 20:16:19 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.it-ninja.xyz/study-notes/routing-bgp/</guid>
      <description>Basics  Distance vector protocol. Uses autonomous systems numbers (ASNs). Uses for connecting to external autonomous systems. eBGP and iBGP.  eBGP is where two routers are in different ASs. iBGP is where two routers are in the sam AS.  Runs over tcp/179. Neighbours (also known as peers) are explicitly defined.  TCP keepalives used for maintaining BGP adjacencies.  Routes must be in the route table to be placed into the BGP table.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>